{
  "questions": [
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Horen Sing Bey",
        "B. Queen Oja",
        "C. Topon Kumar Gogoi",
        "D. Rameswar Teli"
      ],
      "question": "Which candidate wins by highest number of vote difference margin in 2019 Lok Sabha Election",
      "answer": "D. Rameswar Teli"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 7th April, 1937",
        "B. 14th April, 1938",
        "C. 15th September, 1938",
        "D. 4th January, 1939"
      ],
      "question": "The first sitting of Assam Legislative Assembly was held on",
      "answer": "A. 7th April, 1937"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1st State Assembly",
        "B. 3rd State Assembly",
        "C. 4th State Assembly",
        "D. 5th State Assembly"
      ],
      "question": "Which one is the only Assam Assembly that lasted for 6 years",
      "answer": "D. 5th State Assembly"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 2",
        "B. 3",
        "C. 4",
        "D. 5"
      ],
      "question": "Assam contains ______ of six physiographic divisions of India",
      "answer": "B. 3"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1971",
        "B. 1972",
        "C. 1973",
        "D. 1975"
      ],
      "question": "The Pollution Control Board of Assam was established in the year",
      "answer": "D. 1975"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Darrang",
        "B. Nagao",
        "C. Goalpara",
        "D. Kamrup Rural"
      ],
      "question": "The proposed Skill University in Assam will be set up in which District",
      "answer": "A. Darrang"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Bornodi Bhotiai",
        "B. Bulbul Can Sing",
        "C. Mission China",
        "D. Kaaneen"
      ],
      "question": "Which film wins the 2019 Best Assamese Film National Award",
      "answer": "B. Bulbul Can Sing"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. National Register of Citizens",
        "B. National Register of Citizenship",
        "C. National Registretion of Citizens",
        "D. National Registretion of Citizenship"
      ],
      "question": "What is the full form of NRC",
      "answer": "A. National Register of Citizens"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Guwahati",
        "B. Dibrugarh",
        "C. Tezpur",
        "D. Jorhat"
      ],
      "question": "In which city, the first CNG station of Assam is inaugurated",
      "answer": "B. Dibrugarh"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Ajay Lamba",
        "B. Alok Kumar",
        "C. Nani Tagia",
        "D. Arup Kumar Goswami"
      ],
      "question": "Who is sworn in as the Chief Justice of Gauhati High Court in the month of October, 2019",
      "answer": "A. Ajay Lamba"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dibru-Saikhowa",
        "B. Pobitora",
        "C. Chakrashila",
        "D. Bornadi"
      ],
      "question": "Which one is a biosphere reserves in Assam",
      "answer": "A. Dibru-Saikhowa"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Arun Sarma",
        "B. Hemchandra Goswami",
        "C. Banikanta Kakati",
        "D. Atul Chandra Hazarika"
      ],
      "question": "Which Assamese litterateur has been bestowed with the title \"Sahitycharjya\"",
      "answer": "D. Atul Chandra Hazarika"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Jnanadabhiram Barua",
        "B. Jatindra Nath Duwara",
        "C. Padmanath Gohain Baruah",
        "D. Ananda Chandra Agarwala"
      ],
      "question": "Who had translated Laxminath Bezbarua's Burhi aair xadhu into English",
      "answer": "A. Jnanadabhiram Barua"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Hemchandra Goswami",
        "B. Kanaklal Barua",
        "C. Hem Barua",
        "D. Mafizuddin Ahmed Hazarika"
      ],
      "question": "Which one of the following also served as a member of the Viceroy's Executive Council",
      "answer": "B. Kanaklal Barua"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Imran Shah",
        "B. Kanak Sen Deka",
        "C. Rongbong Terang",
        "D. Dhrubajyoti Bora"
      ],
      "question": "Who was the President of the Assam Sahitya Sabha adhibashan held in Guwahati in 2013",
      "answer": "A. Imran Shah"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Rongbong Terang",
        "B. Imran Shah",
        "C. Dhrubajyoti Bora",
        "D. Joyasree Goswami Mahanta"
      ],
      "question": "Who wins the 2019 Sahitya Akademi Award in Assamese language",
      "answer": "D. Joyasree Goswami Mahanta"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Kuladhar Saikia",
        "B. Prahlad Tasa",
        "C. Basanta Kumar Sarma",
        "D. Rati Mohan Nath"
      ],
      "question": "Who is elected as the new President of Assam Sahitya Sabha in the year 2020",
      "answer": "A. Kuladhar Saikia"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Justice Meera Sarma",
        "B. Justice T.C. Das",
        "C. Justice Shafiqul Haque",
        "D. Justice S. P. Rajkhowa"
      ],
      "question": "Who was appointed as the first Lokayukta of Assam",
      "answer": "B. Justice T.C. Das"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dibrugarh",
        "B. Majuli",
        "C. Nalbari",
        "D. Dhubri"
      ],
      "question": "Where the Annual Assam Sahitya Sabha session will be held in the year 2021",
      "answer": "B. Majuli"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 71",
        "B. 74",
        "C. 76",
        "D. 79"
      ],
      "question": "Total number of medals won by Assam in the Khelo India Youth Games 2020, Guwahati",
      "answer": "C. 76"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 3",
        "B. 4",
        "C. 5",
        "D. 6"
      ],
      "question": "How many Gold medal won by Assam Swimmer Shivangi Sarma in the Khelo India Youth Games 2020, Guwahati",
      "answer": "C. 5"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Jadav Payeng",
        "B. Uddhab Bharali",
        "C. Jitendra Nath Goswami",
        "D. None of the Above"
      ],
      "question": "Which activist from Assam has been the \"Swami Vivekananda Karmayogi Award\" in the year 2020",
      "answer": "A. Jadav Payeng"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Golap Chandra Barua",
        "B. Kasinath Tamuli Phukan",
        "C. Hemchandra Goswami",
        "D. Srinath Duara Barbarua"
      ],
      "question": "Tungkhungia Buranji is written by",
      "answer": "D. Srinath Duara Barbarua"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Udayaditya Singha",
        "B. Chakradhwaj Singha",
        "C. Jayadhwaj Singha",
        "D. Pratap Singha"
      ],
      "question": "Name the Ahom king who married the Koch princess Mangola Devi",
      "answer": "D. Pratap Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1618",
        "B. 1622",
        "C. 1626",
        "D. 1628"
      ],
      "question": "When was Lachit Borphukan was born",
      "answer": "B. 1622"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Treaty of Guwahati",
        "B. Treaty of Garhgaon",
        "C. Treaty of Sadiya",
        "D. Treaty of Ghilajharighat"
      ],
      "question": "Which Treaty marks the end of Mir Jumla's occupation of the Ahom capital, Garhgaon",
      "answer": "D. Treaty of Ghilajharighat"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Laluk Sola Buragohain",
        "B. Atan Buragohain",
        "C. Ruchinath Burhagohain",
        "D. Ghanashyam Burhagohain"
      ],
      "question": "Which Burhagohain himself rejected the offer of becoming Ahom King on two occasions",
      "answer": "B. Atan Buragohain"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sukulahuda Burhagohain",
        "B. Sengmun Burhagohain",
        "C. Ruchinath Burhagohain",
        "D. Atan Buragohain"
      ],
      "question": "Who was the second in leadership next to Lachit Barphukan during the battle of Saraighat",
      "answer": "D. Atan Buragohain"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. North Lakhimpur",
        "B. Jorhat",
        "C. Udalguri",
        "D. Dibrugarh"
      ],
      "question": "The Gohain Kamal Ali which was constructed during Nara Narayan, connects Coochbehar to",
      "answer": "A. North Lakhimpur"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1581",
        "B. 1584",
        "C. 1587",
        "D. 1589"
      ],
      "question": "In which year, Koch king Nara Narayan died",
      "answer": "C. 1587"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1558",
        "B. 1561",
        "C. 1562",
        "D. 1563"
      ],
      "question": "In which year, Chilarai managed to occupy the capital of Ahom, Garhgaon",
      "answer": "D. 1563"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 14 cm per km",
        "B. 16 cm per km",
        "C. 17 cm per km",
        "D. 19 cm per km"
      ],
      "question": "The average gradient of the Brahmaputra plain is",
      "answer": "A. 14 cm per km"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 2856 km",
        "B. 2892 km",
        "C. 2900 Km",
        "D. 2953 km"
      ],
      "question": "The total length of the Brahmaputra river is",
      "answer": "C. 2900 Km"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 916 km",
        "B. 925 km",
        "C. 936 Km",
        "D. 968 km"
      ],
      "question": "The total length of the Brahmaputra river in India is",
      "answer": "A. 916 km"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1885",
        "B. 1889",
        "C. 1896",
        "D. 1901"
      ],
      "question": "When Petroleum was first discovered in Assam",
      "answer": "B. 1889"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Tinsukia",
        "B. Jorhat",
        "C. Lakhimpur",
        "D. Dibrugarh"
      ],
      "question": "The Bogibeel Bridge connects the Dhemaji district with which one district",
      "answer": "D. Dibrugarh"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 4.9 km",
        "B. 5.2 km",
        "C. 5.3 km",
        "D. 5.7 km"
      ],
      "question": "What is the total length of the Bogibeel Bridge",
      "answer": "A. 4.9 km"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 2",
        "B. 5",
        "C. 6",
        "D. 7"
      ],
      "question": "Assam has common boundary with Indian states.",
      "answer": "D. 7"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Barak river from Lakhipur-Bhanga",
        "B. River ganga from haldia to Allahabad",
        "C. River Brahmaputra from Dhubri to Sadiya",
        "D. None of These"
      ],
      "question": "Which is the following route is the National Waterway-2?",
      "answer": "C. River Brahmaputra from Dhubri to Sadiya"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dikhou",
        "B. Kameng",
        "C. Dihang",
        "D. Dishang"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following is a headstream of Brahmaputra river?",
      "answer": "C. Dihang"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1889",
        "B. 1899",
        "C. 1999",
        "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "question": "In which year Crude Oil was drilled in Assam for the first time?",
      "answer": "A. 1889"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dima Hasao",
        "B. Kokrajhar",
        "C. Barpeta",
        "D. Sonitpur"
      ],
      "question": "Oak Tasar a wild silkworm is found in which of the following district in Assam?",
      "answer": "A. Dima Hasao"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Barail Range",
        "B. Karbi Plateau",
        "C. Jaintia Hills",
        "D. Lushai Hills"
      ],
      "question": "The origin of Barak river lies in",
      "answer": "A. Barail Range"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Bamboo",
        "B. Sal",
        "C. Hollong",
        "D. Teak"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following tree is predominant in the forests of Assam ?",
      "answer": "B. Sal"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 82 degree E",
        "B. 85 degree E",
        "C. 95 degree E",
        "D. 90 degrees E"
      ],
      "question": "Assam’s proposed Chai-bagaan Time will have reference longitude of",
      "answer": "D. 90 degrees E"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sadiya–Bukaghat",
        "B. Sadiya–Krisnapur",
        "C. Dhola–Sadiya",
        "D. None of the Above"
      ],
      "question": "Which two places have been connected by Bhupen Hazarika Bridge?",
      "answer": "C. Dhola–Sadiya"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Bharali and Bornadi",
        "B. Subansiri and Bharali",
        "C. Dihang and Subansiri",
        "D. Dibang and Dihang"
      ],
      "question": "The Gai, a tributary to Brahmaputra is situated between",
      "answer": "C. Dihang and Subansiri"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Pygmy Hog",
        "B. Golden Langur",
        "C. Greater Adjutant Stork",
        "D. One Horned Rhino"
      ],
      "question": "Purnima Devi Barman from Assam is well known for the conservation effort of which of the following species?",
      "answer": "C. Greater Adjutant Stork"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Barak River",
        "B. Surma River",
        "C. Dibang River",
        "D. Brahmaputra River"
      ],
      "question": "The proposed Tipaimukh Dam is to be constructed over which river?",
      "answer": "A. Barak River"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1960",
        "B. 1970",
        "C. 1980",
        "D. 1990"
      ],
      "question": "Tea auction center was established in \t.",
      "answer": "B. 1970"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Uower",
        "B. Middle",
        "C. Upper",
        "D. None of these"
      ],
      "question": "The Assam districts are major reserves of oil and gas.",
      "answer": "C. Upper"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Fourth",
        "B. Fifth",
        "C. Sixth",
        "D. Seventh"
      ],
      "question": "Which schedule of Indian constitution deals with administration of tribal areas in Assam?",
      "answer": "C. Sixth"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Jorhat",
        "B. Majuli",
        "C. Barpeta",
        "D. Baksa"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following districts of Assam has the highest sex ratio?",
      "answer": "D. Baksa"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Karbi Hills",
        "B. Jaintia Hills",
        "C. Barail Hills",
        "D. Patkai Hills"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following is the highest hill range in Assam?",
      "answer": "C. Barail Hills"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1",
        "B. 2",
        "C. 3",
        "D. 4"
      ],
      "question": "The total number of ramsar sites in Assam is",
      "answer": "A. 1"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Myanmar and Bangladesh",
        "B. Bhutan and Bangladesh",
        "C. China, Myanmar, Bhutan and Bangladesh",
        "D. Myanmar, Bhutan and Bangladesh"
      ],
      "question": "Assam share international border with which of the following countries",
      "answer": "B. Bhutan and Bangladesh"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Jia Dhal",
        "B. Subansiri",
        "C. Jaji",
        "D. Jia Bharali"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following river is known as Kameng in Arunachal Pradesh?",
      "answer": "D. Jia Bharali"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 21 %",
        "B. 34 %",
        "C. 42 %",
        "D. 27 %"
      ],
      "question": "What percentage of total area of Assam is under forest?",
      "answer": "B. 34 %"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Nameri NP",
        "B. Pobitora Wildlife Sanctuary",
        "C. Kaziranga NP",
        "D. Garampani Wildlife Sanctuary"
      ],
      "question": "Swamp Deer has a sizeable population in which of the following protected ared in Assam?",
      "answer": "C. Kaziranga NP"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 320",
        "B. 340",
        "C. 398",
        "D. 424"
      ],
      "question": "What is the population density of Assam per square kilometers?",
      "answer": "C. 398"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 430 km²",
        "B. 799.66 km²",
        "C. 468.55 km²",
        "D. 500 km²"
      ],
      "question": "What is the total area of Kaziranga national park?",
      "answer": "A. 430 km²"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sikkim",
        "B. Nagaland",
        "C. Arunachal Pradesh",
        "D. Bhutan"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following is not connected by border of Assam?",
      "answer": "A. Sikkim"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1985",
        "B. 1971",
        "C. 1947",
        "D. 1960"
      ],
      "question": "In which year, Assamese was adopted as the official language of Assam?",
      "answer": "D. 1960"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1903",
        "B. 1911",
        "C. 1924",
        "D. 1941"
      ],
      "question": "In which year Tocklai Tea Research Institute was established?",
      "answer": "B. 1911"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Chanderdinga Hills",
        "B. Subankhata",
        "C. Silbheta",
        "D. Hahim"
      ],
      "question": "In which of the following area in Assam iron ore deposits are found?",
      "answer": "A. Chanderdinga Hills"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 900 km",
        "B. 1000 km",
        "C. 1500 km",
        "D. 2100 km"
      ],
      "question": "In India, the Brahmaputra river is almost ___ km long.",
      "answer": "A. 900 km"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Manipur",
        "B. Mizoram",
        "C. Sikkim",
        "D. Nagaland"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following state is not situated to the east of Assam?",
      "answer": "B. Mizoram"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1970",
        "B. 1973",
        "C. 1984",
        "D. 1993"
      ],
      "question": "In which year the capital of Assam is shifted from Shillong to Dispur?",
      "answer": "B. 1973"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Barail",
        "B. Singhasan",
        "C. Rengma",
        "D. Dambuksu"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following is the highest peak in Karbi Plateau?",
      "answer": "B. Singhasan"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Namcha Barwa",
        "B. Doda Betta",
        "C. Guru Peak",
        "D. Himagiri"
      ],
      "question": "Which is the highest mountain peak of Assam Himalaya range?",
      "answer": "A. Namcha Barwa"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Kaziranga National Park",
        "B. Dihing Patkai National Park",
        "C. Nameri National Park",
        "D. Pobitord WLS"
      ],
      "question": "Tropical wet evergreen forests are predominantly found in which of the following protected areas?",
      "answer": "B. Dihing Patkai National Park"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Nagaland",
        "B. Mizoram",
        "C. Tripura",
        "D. Manipur"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following North Eastern state shares the shortest boundary with Assam?",
      "answer": "C. Tripura"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Indoburmese ecozone",
        "B. Indomalaya ecozone",
        "C. IndoBangla ecozone",
        "D. Brahmaputra ecozone"
      ],
      "question": "The Kaziranga National park is located in which of the following ecozones?",
      "answer": "B. Indomalaya ecozone"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1839",
        "B. 1899",
        "C. 1900",
        "D. 1918"
      ],
      "question": "When the Tea company of Assam was established?",
      "answer": "A. 1839"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Monsoon seasonb",
        "B. Pre-monsoon season",
        "C. Retreating monsoon season",
        "D. Winter season"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following is associated with Bordoichila in Assam?",
      "answer": "B. Pre-monsoon season"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Second",
        "B. Third",
        "C. Fourth",
        "D. First"
      ],
      "question": "Area wise the rank of Assam among north eastern states is",
      "answer": "A. Second"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Golaghat",
        "B. Karbi Anglong",
        "C. Cachar",
        "D. Dima Hasao"
      ],
      "question": "Jatinga, famous for mass suicide of migratory birds is located in which the following district?",
      "answer": "D. Dima Hasao"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1970",
        "B. 1971",
        "C. 1972",
        "D. 1973"
      ],
      "question": "In which year the Tea Auction Centre in Guwahati was established",
      "answer": "A. 1970"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Bongaigaon",
        "B. Udalguri",
        "C. Chirang",
        "D. Kokrajhar"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following districts of Assam does not come under the jurisdiction of BTC?",
      "answer": "A. Bongaigaon"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Kamrup (M)",
        "B. Darrang",
        "C. Barpeta",
        "D. Sonitpur"
      ],
      "question": "Amchang Wildlife Sanctuary is located in which of the following districts in Assam ?",
      "answer": "A. Kamrup (M)"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dibru",
        "B. Dikhou",
        "C. Disanq",
        "D. Dikrong"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following is a North Bank tributary of Assam?",
      "answer": "D. Dikrong"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 78534 km²",
        "B. 67456 km²",
        "C. 56789 km²",
        "D. 78438 km²"
      ],
      "question": "What is the total land area of assam ?",
      "answer": "D. 78438 km²"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Karimgarj",
        "B. Dhubri",
        "C. Hailakandi",
        "D. Cachar"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following districts of Assam does not have any international boundary with Bangladesh?",
      "answer": "C. Hailakandi"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sankosh",
        "B. Pagladiya",
        "C. Manas",
        "D. Dibru"
      ],
      "question": "Which of following is the westernmost tributary of Brahmaputra ?",
      "answer": "A. Sankosh"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Kaziranga National Park and Orang National Park",
        "B. Kaziranga National Park and Manas National Park",
        "C. Borail Wildlife Sanctuary and Nokrek National Park",
        "D. None of the sites in Assam are UNESCO World Heritage Site"
      ],
      "question": "Which the protective sites of Assam are recognised as UNESCO World Heritage Sites?",
      "answer": "B. Kaziranga National Park and Manas National Park"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 30.1%",
        "B. 24.5%",
        "C. 27.5%",
        "D. 17.7%"
      ],
      "question": "As per 2011 census, the growth rate of population of Assam during the decade of 2001-2011 is",
      "answer": "D. 17.7%"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 21",
        "B. 16",
        "C. 41",
        "D. 31"
      ],
      "question": "Sex ratio wise the rank of Assam among the states of India is",
      "answer": "B. 16"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Rapeseed",
        "B. Tobbaco",
        "C. Soyabean",
        "D. Mesto"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following cash crops is not produced in Assam?",
      "answer": "C. Soyabean"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. High Sulphur content",
        "B. High Moisture content",
        "C. Low Volatile Matter",
        "D. High Ash content"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following is true regarding the coals found in Assam?",
      "answer": "A. High Sulphur content"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sonitpur",
        "B. Sivasagar",
        "C. Darang",
        "D. Dibrugarh"
      ],
      "question": "Which district of Assam has the highest number of Tea gardens ?",
      "answer": "D. Dibrugarh"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Barak",
        "B. Dihang",
        "C. Lohit",
        "D. Brahmaputra"
      ],
      "question": "The Bhupen Hazarika Setu (Dhola–Sadiya Bridge) is constructed over which river?",
      "answer": "C. Lohit"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 69.5 m",
        "B. 92.5 m",
        "C. 56.6 m",
        "D. 79.5 m"
      ],
      "question": "The average height of Assam from sea level is",
      "answer": "D. 79.5 m"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Digboi refinery",
        "B. Barauni refinery",
        "C. Noonmati refinery",
        "D. Numaligarh refinery"
      ],
      "question": "______ is the oldest refinery of IndiA.",
      "answer": "A. Digboi refinery"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Buriburi rainforest",
        "B. Bogibeel rainforest",
        "C. Dehing Patkai rainforest",
        "D. None of these"
      ],
      "question": "The tropical rainforests in Assam is",
      "answer": "C. Dehing Patkai rainforest"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dima Hasao",
        "B. Dhubri",
        "C. Karbi Anglong",
        "D. Hailakandi"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following districts of Assam has the lowest literacy rate?",
      "answer": "B. Dhubri"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Aromatic Rice",
        "B. Winter Rice",
        "C. Summer Rice",
        "D. Autumn Rice"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following is type of rice has the highest production and also highest area under cultivation in Assam?",
      "answer": "A. Aromatic Rice"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Assam Orthodox Tea",
        "B. Muga Silk",
        "C. Gamocha",
        "D. Both [B] and [C]"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following product/products in Assam has/have Geographical Indication (GI) tag?",
      "answer": "D. Both [B] and [C]"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1823",
        "B. 1824",
        "C. 1825",
        "D. 1826"
      ],
      "question": "In which of the following year Tea was discovered in Assam?",
      "answer": "A. 1823"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dhubri",
        "B. Kamrup",
        "C. Nagaon",
        "D. Barpeta"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following districts in Assam has the highest population?",
      "answer": "C. Nagaon"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Karimganj",
        "B. Tezpur",
        "C. Silchar",
        "D. Mangaldoi"
      ],
      "question": "Which Lok Sabha constituency of Assam is reserved for SC?",
      "answer": "A. Karimganj"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Nameri National Park",
        "B. Garampani Wildlife Sanctuary",
        "C. Dibru Saikhowa National Park",
        "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following area in Assam is known for Feral Horses?",
      "answer": "C. Dibru Saikhowa National Park"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 68%",
        "B. 72%",
        "C. 82%",
        "D. 85%"
      ],
      "question": "As per the data of 2011 population census, the literacy rate in Assam is approximately",
      "answer": "B. 72%"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1935",
        "B. 1948",
        "C. 1958",
        "D. 1967"
      ],
      "question": "When did Transport Department of Assam was established?",
      "answer": "B. 1948"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dima Hasao and Karbi Anglong",
        "B. Hojai and Barpeta",
        "C. Nagaon and Morigaon",
        "D. Kukrajhar and Golaghat"
      ],
      "question": "The major reserves of limestone are in _____ and",
      "answer": "A. Dima Hasao and Karbi Anglong"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 15",
        "B. 24",
        "C. 26",
        "D. 10"
      ],
      "question": "Population wise rank of Assam among the states of India is",
      "answer": "A. 15"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. First",
        "B. Second",
        "C. Third",
        "D. Fourth"
      ],
      "question": "The rank of Assam in terms of crude oil production is _____.",
      "answer": "B. Second"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Myanmar, Bhutan and Bangladesh",
        "B. Bhutan and Bangladesh",
        "C. China, Myanmar, Bhutan and Bangladesh",
        "D. Myanmar and Bangladesh"
      ],
      "question": "Assam share international border with which of the following countries",
      "answer": "B. Bhutan and Bangladesh"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Mike Pandey",
        "B. Sunderlal Bahuguna",
        "C. Jadav Payeng",
        "D. Kallen Pakkudan"
      ],
      "question": "Who is famously known as the “Forest Man of India”?",
      "answer": "C. Jadav Payeng"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Nameri National Park",
        "B. Pobitora Wildlife Sanctuary",
        "C. Garampani Wildlife Sanctuary",
        "D. Chakrasila Wildlife Sanctuary"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following protected areas in Assam is known for Golden Langur",
      "answer": "D. Chakrasila Wildlife Sanctuary"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 30 November, 2004",
        "B. 10 February, 2003",
        "D. 20 June, 2005"
      ],
      "question": "When did B.T.A.D was established ?",
      "answer": "B. 10 February, 2003"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 23",
        "B. 27",
        "C. 32",
        "D. 34"
      ],
      "question": "The total number of administrative districts in Assam is _________.",
      "answer": "D. 34"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 13",
        "B. 33",
        "C. 80",
        "D. 126"
      ],
      "question": "The total number of seats in the legislative council of Assam is \t.",
      "answer": "D. 126"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Tobacco",
        "B. Rubber",
        "C. Maize",
        "D. Paddy"
      ],
      "question": "Assam is not a traditional growing area of which of the following crop?",
      "answer": "A. Tobacco"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dilli Jaypore",
        "B. Mikir Hills",
        "C. Singrimari Hills",
        "D. Makum"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following is the largest Coalfield in Assam?",
      "answer": "D. Makum"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 14",
        "B. 24",
        "C. 34",
        "D. 44"
      ],
      "question": "The percentage of population living in urban areas in Assam according to 2011 census is",
      "answer": "A. 14"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 17.2 %",
        "B. 20.6 %",
        "C. 22.4 %",
        "D. 34.21 %"
      ],
      "question": "How much land of assam has been occupied by forests?",
      "answer": "D. 34.21 %"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dhemaji",
        "B. Kokrajhar",
        "C. Baks",
        "D. Cachar"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following districts of Assam does not have any international boundary?",
      "answer": "A. Dhemaji"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sonbill Lake",
        "B. Kumri Beel Lake",
        "C. Cahndubi Lake",
        "D. Deepor Beel"
      ],
      "question": "Which of is the largest wetland in Assam?",
      "answer": "A. Sonbill Lake"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 2006",
        "B. 2007",
        "C. 2008",
        "D. 2009"
      ],
      "question": "In which year Kaziranga National Park became a Tiger reserve?",
      "answer": "A. 2006"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Ronga Noi",
        "B. Borgang",
        "C. Jhanji",
        "D. Bhugdoi"
      ],
      "question": "Which is the northward flow sub-river of Brahmaputra?",
      "answer": "C. Jhanji"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1825",
        "B. 1867",
        "C. 1889",
        "D. 1901"
      ],
      "question": "In which of the following year Coal was discovered in Assam?",
      "answer": "A. 1825"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Guwahati",
        "B. Bongaigaon",
        "C. Numalighar",
        "D. Makum"
      ],
      "question": "Asia’s first successful mechanically drilled oil well was drilled in ________ of Assam way back in 1867.",
      "answer": "D. Makum"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Karbi Hills and Dima Hasao",
        "B. Majuli Island",
        "C. Brahmaputrd Floodplains of Eastern Assam",
        "D. BTAD gred near Bhutan Himalayan foothills"
      ],
      "question": "Red Laterite Soils are found in which of the following areas in Assam",
      "answer": "A. Karbi Hills and Dima Hasao"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 640 km",
        "B. 720 km",
        "C. 920 km",
        "D. 2880 km"
      ],
      "question": "The length of Brahmaputra within Assam is ______.",
      "answer": "B. 720 km"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 25%",
        "B. 55%",
        "C. 75%",
        "D. 85%"
      ],
      "question": "The approximate share of Assam in India’s annually production of tea is",
      "answer": "B. 55%"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dibru-Saikhowa National Park",
        "B. Kaziranga National Park",
        "C. Orang National Park",
        "D. Manas National Park"
      ],
      "question": "Which National Park in Assam is one of the last strongholds for the wild water buffalo?",
      "answer": "B. Kaziranga National Park"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Pobitord WLS",
        "B. Sonai Rupai WLS",
        "C. Bornodi WLS",
        "D. Garampani WLS"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following is the oldest among the present eighteen wildlife sanctuaries in Assam?",
      "answer": "D. Garampani WLS"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Kamrup Metropolitan",
        "B. Nagaon",
        "C. Tinisuki",
        "D. Nalbari"
      ],
      "question": "The literacy rate of which of the following districts is highest in Assam?",
      "answer": "A. Kamrup Metropolitan"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 65.21%",
        "B. 67.27%",
        "C. 78.81%",
        "D. 88.90%"
      ],
      "question": "Literacy rate of women in assam according to 2011 census?",
      "answer": "B. 67.27%"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1950",
        "B. 1972",
        "C. 1974",
        "D. 1975"
      ],
      "question": "When Assam’s Kaziranga was declared as a national park ?",
      "answer": "C. 1974"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1839",
        "B. 1849",
        "C. 1859",
        "D. 1869"
      ],
      "question": "In which year a earthquake sank the bank of the Barak by 15 ft.?",
      "answer": "D. 1869"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Singhason",
        "B. Laikei peak",
        "C. Danbukosu peak",
        "D. Mahadev"
      ],
      "question": "What is the highest peak of Karbi hill ?",
      "answer": "A. Singhason"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Tropic of cancer",
        "B. Equator",
        "C. Tropic of Capricorn",
        "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following geographical lines passes through the state of Assam?",
      "answer": "D. None of the above"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dibrugarh",
        "B. Tezpur",
        "C. Jorhat",
        "D. None of these"
      ],
      "question": "Assam’s newest district Majuli is carved out of which of district?",
      "answer": "C. Jorhat"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Tamulpur",
        "B. Mushalpur",
        "C. Barpeta Road",
        "D. Goreswar"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following is the district Headquarter of newly created Baksa District.",
      "answer": "B. Mushalpur"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Subansiri",
        "B. Dhansiri",
        "C. Manas",
        "D. Sonai"
      ],
      "question": "Which among the following is not a principal tributary of Brahmaputra?",
      "answer": "D. Sonai"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Mizoram",
        "B. Meghalaya",
        "C. Nagaland",
        "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following North Eastern state shares the longest boundary with Assam?",
      "answer": "B. Meghalaya"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Guwahati",
        "B. Itanagar",
        "C. Dispur",
        "D. Agartala"
      ],
      "question": "What is the capital of Assam?",
      "answer": "C. Dispur"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Nilachal Hill",
        "B. Chitrachal Hill",
        "C. Sandhyachal Hill",
        "D. Jogini Hill"
      ],
      "question": "In which hill top, the Kamakhya Temple is located?",
      "answer": "A. Nilachal Hill"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Bishnuram Medhi",
        "B. Tarun Ram Phukan",
        "C. Gopinath Bordoloi",
        "D. None of the Above"
      ],
      "question": "Who was the first Chief Minister of Assam?",
      "answer": "C. Gopinath Bordoloi"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1671",
        "B. 1644",
        "C. 1678",
        "D. 1643"
      ],
      "question": "The war of Saraighat was fought between Ahom and Mughal in the year?",
      "answer": "A. 1671"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Jorhat",
        "B. Sualkuchi",
        "C. Diphu",
        "D. Digboi"
      ],
      "question": "Which town is also known as the Manchester of Assam?",
      "answer": "B. Sualkuchi"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1458",
        "B. 1549",
        "C. 1449",
        "D. 1464"
      ],
      "question": "Srimanta Sankardev was born in the year __.",
      "answer": "C. 1449"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 34",
        "B. 32",
        "C. 25",
        "D. 33"
      ],
      "question": "Total number of Districts in Assam are __.",
      "answer": "A. 34"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Godadhar Singha",
        "B. Rudra Singha",
        "C. Siva Singha",
        "D. Pramatta Singha"
      ],
      "question": "The Temple of Umananda was built by:",
      "answer": "A. Godadhar Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. The Mahabharata",
        "B. The Harshacharita",
        "C. The Kalika Purana",
        "D. The Arthashastra"
      ],
      "question": "One of the following books is the most important literature source for the study of early history of Assam. Which is the book?",
      "answer": "C. The Kalika Purana"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Mahiranga Danava",
        "B. Narakasura",
        "C. Bhaskara Varman",
        "D. Naranarayana"
      ],
      "question": "The earliest king of Assam was",
      "answer": "A. Mahiranga Danava"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Palas",
        "B. Varmans",
        "C. Narakas",
        "D. Salastambhas"
      ],
      "question": "The earliest historical dynasty of Assam was that of",
      "answer": "B. Varmans"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Autobiographical writings of the Ahom rulers",
        "B. Diaries written by the monarchs",
        "C. Chronicles",
        "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "question": "The Buranjis are",
      "answer": "C. Chronicles"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Bhagadatta",
        "B. Kumar Bhaskar Barman",
        "C. Swargadeo Rudra Singha",
        "D. Kumar Rudra Barman"
      ],
      "question": "Hiuen Tsang visited Assam (kamarupa) in 640 AD. He was received by the king",
      "answer": "B. Kumar Bhaskar Barman"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 13th century",
        "B. 14th century",
        "C. 15th century",
        "D. 10th century"
      ],
      "question": "Ibn Battuta, the celebrated traveler visited Assam in the",
      "answer": "B. 14th century"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Suryakhan Daikegya",
        "B. Dibar and Dodosai",
        "C. Sukumar Barkaith",
        "D. Rama Saraswati"
      ],
      "question": "The illustration work of the medieval Assamese text Hastividyarnava was done by",
      "answer": "C. Sukumar Barkaith"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Nara Narayan",
        "B. Parkshit Narayan",
        "C. Biswa Singha",
        "D. Raghu Dev"
      ],
      "question": "Gohain Kamal Ali constructed by Gohain Kamal from Koch Bihar to Narayanpur was constructed during the reign of",
      "answer": "A. Nara Narayan"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Rudra Singha",
        "B. Siva Singha",
        "C. Rajeswar Singha",
        "D. Pramatta Singha"
      ],
      "question": "Rang Ghar was constructed during the period of",
      "answer": "D. Pramatta Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Indra Narayan",
        "B. Joso Narayan",
        "C. Nirbhya Narayan",
        "D. Durlabh Narayan"
      ],
      "question": "The Kachari king to assume the title Pratap Narayan after defeating the Ahom was",
      "answer": "A. Indra Narayan"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Ram Saraswati",
        "B. Ananta Kandali",
        "C. Sankardeva",
        "D. Madhav Kandali"
      ],
      "question": "Who among the literatures did not receive the patronage of Koch king Naranarayan ?",
      "answer": "D. Madhav Kandali"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Alberuni",
        "B. Azan Fakir",
        "C. Mir Jumla",
        "D. Shihabuddin Tallish"
      ],
      "question": "Fatiyah-i-Ibryah was written by",
      "answer": "D. Shihabuddin Tallish"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sankardeva",
        "B. Madhav Kandali",
        "C. Ananta Kandali",
        "D. Ram Saraswati"
      ],
      "question": "Who among the following is the first Assamese translator of Ramayana?",
      "answer": "B. Madhav Kandali"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Karbi Anglong",
        "B. Khasi-Jaintia (Meghalaya)",
        "C. Manipur",
        "D. Tripura"
      ],
      "question": "The Barak or Surma river of Cacher originates from",
      "answer": "C. Manipur"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Shiva Singha",
        "B. Pratap Singha",
        "C. Jayadhvaj Singha",
        "D. Suhungmung"
      ],
      "question": "The first Ahom Monarch to assume the Hindu title Swarga Narayan of was",
      "answer": "D. Suhungmung"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Borphukan",
        "B. Rajkhowa",
        "C. Barpatra Gohain",
        "D. Khongea Barua"
      ],
      "question": "The title of overall administration head of lower Assam Region during the Ahom rule was",
      "answer": "A. Borphukan"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Chandrakanta Singha",
        "B. Kamaleshwar Singha",
        "C. Jogeshwar Singha",
        "D. Purandar Singha"
      ],
      "question": "The independent Ahom king was",
      "answer": "D. Purandar Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Zamindar",
        "B. King",
        "C. Frontier Officer",
        "D. Naval Commander"
      ],
      "question": "Sadiya Khowa Gohain was a",
      "answer": "C. Frontier Officer"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sutiyampha",
        "B. Sutamla",
        "C. Surampha",
        "D. Sunyatpha"
      ],
      "question": "The King nicknamed as Bhagaraja was",
      "answer": "C. Surampha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Elaborate burial tanks of Ahom nobility are kings",
        "B. Large fields",
        "C. Temples",
        "D. Enclosure for sporting activities"
      ],
      "question": "Maidams are",
      "answer": "A. Elaborate burial tanks of Ahom nobility are kings"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sudangpha Raja",
        "B. Suhungmung Dihingia",
        "C. Pratap Singha",
        "D. Jayadhvaj Singha"
      ],
      "question": "The officer of the Barbarua and Barphukan is created by",
      "answer": "C. Pratap Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Shiva Singha",
        "B. Pramatta Singha",
        "C. Rajehwar Singha",
        "D. Lakshmi Singha"
      ],
      "question": "Rudra Singha built the Rang Ghar with Bamboo and WooD. It was built by brick and motor by",
      "answer": "B. Pramatta Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Rajmantri Atanu Borgohain Dihingia Raja",
        "B. Koliabhumora Barphukan",
        "C. Miri Sandiloi",
        "D. Manthir Bharali Barua"
      ],
      "question": "In the Battle of Saraighat next to Lachit Barphukan was in the leadership of",
      "answer": "A. Rajmantri Atanu Borgohain Dihingia Raja"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Chandrakanta Singha",
        "B. Kamaleshwar Singha",
        "C. Jogeswar Singha",
        "D. Purandar Singha"
      ],
      "question": "The last independent Ahom King was",
      "answer": "D. Purandar Singha"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. East India Company and Ahom King",
        "B. East India Company and Burmese",
        "C. British King and the Ahom King",
        "D. Ahom King and Burmese"
      ],
      "question": "The Treaty of Yandaboo was signed in 1826 between",
      "answer": "B. East India Company and Burmese"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Lakshminath Bezbaruah",
        "B. Chandrakumar Agarwalla",
        "C. Hemchandra Goswami",
        "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "question": "Who did not belong to Jonaki Yug?",
      "answer": "D. None of the above"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Piyali phukan",
        "B. Maniram Dewan",
        "C. Gomdhar Konwar",
        "D. Piyali Barua"
      ],
      "question": "The first rebellion against the British rule in Assam in 1828 was led by",
      "answer": "C. Gomdhar Konwar"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Chittagong",
        "B. Khulna",
        "C. Sylhet",
        "D. Shala Shakar"
      ],
      "question": "Which district was separated from Assam and given to East Pakistan?",
      "answer": "C. Sylhet"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Sivsagar",
        "B. Lakhimpur",
        "C. Golaghat",
        "D. Sylhet"
      ],
      "question": "Under the Mountbatten plan, a referendum in Assam was to be held in the district of",
      "answer": "D. Sylhet"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Chandraprabha Saikiani",
        "B. Pushpalata Das",
        "C. Rani Gaidinliu",
        "D. None of them"
      ],
      "question": "A pioneer lady responsible for farming the Mrityu Bahini in Assam in connection with the freedom struggle of the country as",
      "answer": "B. Pushpalata Das"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Quit India Movement",
        "B. Civil Disobedience Movement",
        "C. Non-Cooperation Movement",
        "D. Ahom Association"
      ],
      "question": "The shanti Sena Force was formed in Assam during the independence movement before the commencement of the",
      "answer": "A. Quit India Movement"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1920",
        "B. 1921",
        "C. 1922",
        "D. 1923"
      ],
      "question": "When was Assam Provincial Congress formed?",
      "answer": "B. 1921"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Nathan Brown",
        "B. Jatindranath Duwara",
        "C. Debendranath Bezbarua",
        "D. Gunabhiram Barua"
      ],
      "question": "The author of Asomiya Sahityar Buranji is",
      "answer": "C. Debendranath Bezbarua"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1874",
        "B. 1889",
        "C. 1861",
        "D. 1826"
      ],
      "question": "The Assam region was separated from the Bengal presidency in",
      "answer": "A. 1874"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. August 1942",
        "B. August 1842",
        "C. September 1942",
        "D. August 1941"
      ],
      "question": "The British-made aerodrome at Barnagar, Sarbhog, was set ablaze under the leadership of Brajanath Sarma in",
      "answer": "A. August 1942"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Dutiram Barua",
        "B. Piyali Barua",
        "C. Piyali Phukan",
        "D. Farmud Ali"
      ],
      "question": "Who was hanged with Maniram Dewan?",
      "answer": "B. Piyali Barua"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Phulaguri Dhawa",
        "B. Rangia Revolt",
        "C. Patharughat Revolt",
        "D. None of the Above"
      ],
      "question": "Year 1894 is  related to",
      "answer": "C. Patharughat Revolt"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Assamese was reinstated as an official language of Assam",
        "B. Bengali was introduced as an official language of Assam",
        "C. First Assamese novel was published",
        "D. First magazine was published from Calcutta"
      ],
      "question": "1836 was crucial in case of Assamese language and literature because",
      "answer": "B. Bengali was introduced as an official language of Assam"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Garo",
        "B. Bodos",
        "C. Missing",
        "D. Rabha"
      ],
      "question": "Bagurumba is a folk dance performed by:",
      "answer": "B. Bodos"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Cane",
        "B. Bamboo",
        "C. Buffalo horn",
        "D. Teakwood"
      ],
      "question": "Gagana is a famous musical instrument of Assam made up of",
      "answer": "B. Bamboo"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 80,645 km2",
        "B. 78,438 km2",
        "C. 79,012 km2",
        "D. 77,901 km2"
      ],
      "question": "The total area of Assam is",
      "answer": "B. 78,438 km2"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. North zone",
        "B. East zone",
        "C. South zone",
        "D. West zone"
      ],
      "question": "Terai zone is situated at Assam’s"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 3.39 per cent",
        "B. 2.39 per cent",
        "C. 4.39 per cent",
        "D. 2.93 per cent"
      ],
      "question": "How much percent of the Indian landmass is covered by the state of Assam?",
      "answer": "B. 2.39 per cent"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Graphite",
        "B. Rock Salt",
        "C. Limestone",
        "D. Coal"
      ],
      "question": "North Cacher Hill is known for",
      "answer": "C. Limestone"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Bodoland Area",
        "B. North Cacher Hill Area",
        "C. Barak Valley Region",
        "D. Brahmaputra Valley Region"
      ],
      "question": "In Assam, Red soil is the main feature of",
      "answer": "B. North Cacher Hill Area"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Barpeta, Nalbari and Kamrup",
        "B. Goalpara and Kokrajhar",
        "C. Bongaigaon and Kokrajhar",
        "D. Darang, Barpeta and Nalbari"
      ],
      "question": "Baksa district of Assam was created from the parts of which of the following districts?",
      "answer": "A. Barpeta, Nalbari and Kamrup"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Tropical climate",
        "B. Hot climate",
        "C. Warm Climate",
        "D. Cold climate"
      ],
      "question": "Assam state enjoys",
      "answer": "A. Tropical climate"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Nameri",
        "B. Dibru Saikhowa",
        "C. Manas",
        "D. Orang"
      ],
      "question": "The National Park of Assam where the rare winged duck (deohanh) is found in",
      "answer": "A. Nameri"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 33 per cent",
        "B. 22 per cent",
        "C. 28 per cent",
        "D. 19 per cent"
      ],
      "question": "Of the total geographical area of Assam the total area under the forest is",
      "answer": "B. 22 per cent"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1974",
        "B. 1975",
        "C. 1976",
        "D. 1977"
      ],
      "question": "In which year, Kaziranga Wildlife Sanctuary was elevated to a National Park?",
      "answer": "A. 1974"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Jorhat",
        "B. Golaghat",
        "C. Sivsagar",
        "D. Dhemaji"
      ],
      "question": "Pani Dihing Birds Sanctuary is located in which of the following districts of Assam?",
      "answer": "C. Sivsagar"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Kaziranga, Manas, Nameri, Dibru Saikhowa, Orang",
        "B. Manas, Kaziranga, Dibru Saikhowa, Nameri, Orang",
        "C. Kaziranga, Manas, Nameri, Orang, Dibru Saikhowa",
        "D. Manas, Dibru Saikhowa, Kaziranga, Orang, Nameri"
      ],
      "question": "Arrange the National Parks of Assam correctly in the order of descending size",
      "answer": "B. Manas, Kaziranga, Dibru Saikhowa, Nameri, Orang"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. State Cabinet",
        "B. Parliament",
        "C. State Legislature",
        "D. State Public Service Commission"
      ],
      "question": "The Governor of a state is an integral part of the",
      "answer": "C. State Legislature"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. The Speaker of the Lok Sabha and the Speaker of State Legislative Assembly",
        "B. The Solicitor General of India and the Advocate General of the State",
        "C. The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of India and the Chief Justice of High Court of the State",
        "D. None of them"
      ],
      "question": "Who administer the Oath of Office for the president of India and the Governor of a State respectively?",
      "answer": "C. The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of India and the Chief Justice of High Court of the State"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. 1 Year",
        "B. 6 months",
        "C. 3 months",
        "D. Indefinite"
      ],
      "question": "The maximum permissible period between two sessions of a state legislature Assembly is:",
      "answer": "B. 6 months"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Article 220",
        "B. Article 229",
        "C. Article 224",
        "D. Article 231"
      ],
      "question": "Under which of the following Articles, additional and acting judges can be appointed in the High Courts?",
      "answer": "C. Article 224"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. The Governor",
        "B. The judges of the High Court",
        "C. The Chief Minister",
        "D. The President"
      ],
      "question": "In India, who appoints the District Judges?",
      "answer": "A. The Governor"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Jorhat Tea Company",
        "B. Assam Tea Company",
        "C. Assam – Bengal Tea Company",
        "D. None of the above"
      ],
      "question": "The first tea company established in Assam was",
      "answer": "B. Assam Tea Company"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Brass – smiths",
        "B. Bell metal – smiths",
        "C. Ivory artists",
        "D. Potters and blacksmiths"
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following cottage industry workers in Assam suffer most due to the paucity of raw material?",
      "answer": "C. Ivory artists"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Goalpara District",
        "B. Barak Valley",
        "C. Dhubri District",
        "D. Tinsukia District"
      ],
      "question": "The terra – cotta industry in Assam has developed in",
      "answer": "C. Dhubri District"
    },
    {
      "options": [
        "A. Oxo – alcohols",
        "B. Portland cement and hollow bricks",
        "C. Ethylene and propylene",
        "D. Polyethylene"
      ],
      "question": "The Assam Gas Cracker Project does not have the proposal to produce",
      "answer": "B. Portland cement and hollow bricks"
    }
  ]
}
